http://www.anythinglefthanded.co.uk/about/privacy-policy.html

Start ShoppingBasketCheckout
HomeLH ShoppingDelivery detailsBest SellersTop Rated ProductsLatest ArrivalsLeft Handed Product VideosHow Left Handed Products WorkDocumentsGift IdeasChildrens GiftsGift Ideas Under £10.00Gift Ideas £10 - £20Gift Ideas Over £20Gifts For AdultsGifts Under £10.00Gift Ideas £10 - £25Gift Ideas Over £25SetsLeft Handed EssentialsKitchen EssentialsSchool EssentialsWriting EssentialsWritingPacks and Gift SetsPacks and Gift SetsLeft Handed PensCartridge PensRefills for Cartridge PensNon-Smudge PensStabilo Non-Smudge PensStabilo EASY Pens and PencilsMaped PensYoropensGriffix Writing SystemCalligraphy PensWriting AidsGuides and BooksGrips and AccessoriesRulersPencils, grips and sharpenersLeft-Handed PencilsPencil GripsPencil SharpenersScissorsScissor SetsGeneral Purpose ScissorsChildren's scissorsManicure scissors & setsDressmaking scissorsSpecialist ScissorsChildrenSets of Children's EssentialsSets of Children's EssentialsPens & PencilsCartridge PensRefills for Cartridge PensNon-Smudge PensPencils, Fibretips & RollerballsStabilo Left Handed PensYoropens And PencilsGriffix Writing SystemCalligraphy for ChildrenScissorsScissorsSchool EquipmentRulersPencil SharpenersSpiral NotebooksBooks and Writing AidsGuides and BooksWriting Practice BooksWriting AidsFun and gamesFun and gamesHome & OfficePacks and Gift SetsPacks and Gift SetsKitchenChef KnivesPeelersTin OpenersCorkscrewsFood PreparationOther Kitchen UtensilsOfficeComputer AccessoriesOffice ScissorsOffice PensCalendars and PlannersSpiral NotebooksFoldersLeft Handed RulersPencil SharpenersGardenGardenDIYTape measuresPocket KnivesCraft Knives and CuttersWallpaper scissorsLifestyleStationeryLeft-Handed Spiral NotepadsFoldersRulersPencil SharpenersPrinted productsPrinted productsPersonalCalendars and PlannersWallets and PursesPocket KnivesClocks and WatchesClothing and accessoriesFun and gamesBooksAbout Being Left HandedGuides and ManualsLearning Guitar Left HandedBooks for ChildrenDownload EbooksProducts we cannot getInternal Use Only - do not order from this sectionBlog & Info PagesAbout Us & HelpAbout ALHCustomer CommentsContact UsPrivacy PolicyQuestions & HelpLeft Handers ClubJoin The ClubLeft Handers DayBackwards Calendar Product infoHow Things Are Left-HandedProduct VideosPrinted Product CatalogMusic Left HandedWholesale and TradeBeing left-handedLeft handed childrenLeft-handed informationFamous Left-HandersRecreationsResearchBlog & Info PagesAbout UsContact UsQuestions & HelpLeft Handers ClubProduct InfoLeft-Handed ChildrenLeft-Handed InformationAdvantages Of Being LHRecreationsResearchBlog Posts
Anything Left-Handed > About Us > Privacy policy
Anything Left-Handed Privacy Policy
This website is owned and run by Anything Left-Handed Limited, registered in England since 1968 with company number 937338.
We are registered with the UK Data Protection Registrar, 2017, registration number ZA294794.  We are also subject to the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulations (“GDPR”) and aim to comply with the spirit and detail of all EU and UK data protection and personal privacy requirements.
At Anything Left-Handed, we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.
We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.
Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to Keith Milsom, enquiries@anythinglefthanded.co.uk or by writing to Anything Left-Handed, Unit 113, 14 & 15 Admiralty Way, Camberley, Surrey, GU15 3DT. Alternatively, you can telephone 01737 888269.
Who are we?
We are Anything Left-Handed, the world’s leading supplier of left-handed products since we were founded in 1968 and have organised the Left-Handers Club and its newsletters since 1990.
How do we collect information from you?
We obtain information about you when you use our website.  For example, when you enter personal information when placing an order for our products and services, register to receive our Left-Handers Club newsletters or complete a contact form to get in touch with us.
What type of information is collected from you?
The personal information we ask you to enter might include your name, address, email address and in addition to that we may capture your IP address and information regarding what pages are accessed and when. If you make a purchase, your card or other payment information is not held by us, it is collected by our third-party payment processors, who specialise in the secure online capture and processing of payment transactions, as explained below.
If you want to receive our Left-Handers Club email newsletters, we only need your email address and name.
How is your information used?
We may use your information to:
Process orders that you have submitted, including sending you an order confirmation email and a despatch confirmation email;
Contact you regarding any issues with your order or clarifications we need to process it correctly;
Send you information you have requested, such as our guides on left-handedness and how to help left-handed children
Send communications which you have requested and that may be of interest to you, including our Left-Handers Club email newsletters;
Seek your views or comments on the products and services we provide;
Notify you of changes to our product range or services.
Lawful basis for collecting and processing your information
When you place an order for left-handed products:
Contract – when you place an order, we collect your name, email address, mailing address and phone number so we can:
Confirm that your order has been received by email
Contact you by phone and/or email if there are any queries on your order or payment
Deliver the items you ordered by post / courier
Confirm that your order has been despatched by email
Provide any relevant information (for example email / phone number) to the postal service / courier that they require to complete their regulatory / import / export duties
Legal Requirement – we are required by law in the United Kingdom to keep your invoice details for 6 years from the 31 January in the tax year when your order was placed
Legitimate Interest – we may contact you occasionally with details about new left-handed products or offers that may interest you. You can opt-out of these communications when you place your order for goods or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in any email we send you.
When you subscribe for our Left-Handers Club email newsletters:
Consent – We collect your email address and name so we can send you the newsletters and address you personally and ask you to consent to us doing that.  Our newsletters contain a wide variety of information about being left-handed as well as information on left-handed products and occasional discount offers to Left-Handers Club members. You can opt-out of these communications when you place your order for goods or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in any email we send you.
How long do we keep your personal details?
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis and do not keep it for longer than we need to.
We are legally required to hold your name and address as part of a product order for 6 years.
We will hold your name and email address registered for our Left-Handers Club newsletter until you unsubscribe or ask to leave in some other way.
We will hold any details you send to us in an email or contact form until we think there is no further likelihood of needing it for ongoing correspondence, but no longer than 6 years.
Who has access to your information?
We will not sell or rent your information to third parties.
We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.
Third Party Service Providers working on our behalf: We may hold your name and email address with a third-party specialist service provider for the purpose of sending you our email newsletters. However, when we use third party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service (your name and email address) and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes or share it with anyone else.
Please be reassured that we will not release your information to third parties outside of Anything Left-Handed for them to use for their own direct marketing purposes, unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime.
When you enter any payment information on our website for an order, we do not see or collect any card information or Paypal details – these are entered directly on the secure pages of the payment service provider and will be retained by them under their own privacy and data protection policies that you can see on their pages at the time of entering your details.
Your choices
We will need to contact you to confirm your product order has been received and despatched and possibly to resolve any issues preventing completion of your order.  Beyond that, you have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive communications from us about our left-handed products and information on being left-handed, you can tick the opt-out box by your personal details when you place your order.
If you do not want to provide your personal information in our shopping cart pages, we will not be able to accept and despatch your order.
You can request to stop receiving our information at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our email newsletters, contacting us by email: enquiries@anythinglefthanded.co.uk or telephoning us on 01737 888269.
How you can access and update your information
The accuracy of your information is important to us and we want to make it easy for you to review and correct the information that we hold about you. To make changes, you can click the “Update your subscription” link at the bottom of any of our email newsletters, email us at: enquiries@anythinglefthanded.co.uk or write to Anything Left-Handed, Unit 113, 14 & 15 Admiralty Way, Camberley, Surrey, GU15 3DT. Alternatively, you can telephone 01737 888269.
You also have the right to ask for a copy of the information Anything Left-Handed hold about you – please contact us as above.
Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information
When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it’s treated securely. We do not hold any sensitive information such as credit or debit card details and we do not ask for any personal information apart from your name, address, email and phone number as appropriate.
We send our email confirmations for orders and also our newsletters normally over the Internet and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.
We have a written document setting out our Data Protection policies that is reviewed regularly and audited internally for compliance. As a security measure, we do not publish this document on our website, but if you have any concerns or queries please contact us and we will do our best to provide any information you want.
Profiling
We do not collect or hold any personal information to create a profile of your interests and preferences, beyond the items that you have purchased from us. Our payment service provider may reference your payment details against additional information about you from external sources to help protect you by detecting and reducing fraud and credit card risks.
Our blog
Should you choose to add a comment to any posts that we have published on our blog pages, the name and email address you enter with your comment will be saved to this website’s database, along with your computer’s IP address and the time and date that you submitted the comment. This information is only used to identify you as a contributor to the comment section of the respective blog post and is not passed on to any of the third-party data processors detailed below. Only your name will be shown on the public-facing website although if the supplied email address is linked to a Gravatar account, your Gravatar photo will also be displayed.
Your comment and its associated personal data will remain on this site until we see fit to either remove the comment or remove the blog post. Should you wish to have the comment and its associated personal data deleted, please email us using the email address that you commented with and giving the page url for the web page where your comment is displaying.
If you are under 16 years of age you MUST obtain parental consent before posting a comment on our blog.
NOTE: You should avoid entering personally identifiable information into the actual comment field of any blog post comments that you submit on our website as they will be shown publicly on the website.
Email newsletter
If you choose to join our email newsletter, the email address that you submit to us will be forwarded to a third party processor such as ActiveCampaign who provide us with email delivery services. We consider ActiveCampaign to be a third party data processor (see section below). The email address that you submit will not be stored in the Anything Left-Handed website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems and email will be sent to you direct from ActiveCampaign.
Your email address will remain within ActiveCampaign’s database for as long as we continue to use their services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.
If you are under 16 years of age you MUST obtain parental consent before joining our email newsletter.
Site visit tracking
Like most websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website.
Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to us. GA also records your computer’s IP address which could be used to personally identify you but Google do not grant us access to this. We consider Google to be a third-party data processor.
GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found in Google’s developer guides. Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website, but may also mean that you cannot use parts of our website.
Use of ‘cookies'
Like many other websites, the Anything Left-Handed website uses cookies. ‘Cookies' are small pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognise you when you visit. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and do not identify you as an individual. For example, we use cookies to store the details of your shopping cart as you browse our site. This helps us to improve our website and deliver a better more personalised service.
It is possible to switch off cookies by setting your browser preferences, but you would not then be able to order our left-handed products. For more information on how to switch off cookies on your computer, visit our full cookies policy. Turning cookies off may result in a loss of functionality when using our website.
Links to other websites
Our website contains some links to related or additional information on websites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website.
In addition, if you linked to our website from a third-party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site.
16 or Under
We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.
Transferring your information outside of Europe
As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Union (“EU”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU.  We also use email handling services for processing email correspondence and sending our newsletters and these services may transfer your personal information to countries outside the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK but we will ensure that the companies we work with do maintain high standards of data protetction. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Policy.
By submitting your personal data, you are agreeing to this potential transfer, storing or processing of your information.
If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU in order to provide you with those services.
Third-Party data processors
We sometimes use other companies to hold and process some parts of our information and provide services to our customers and we may transfer some of your personal details to them.  We have included details for these companies and the processing they undertake below and we take steps to check that all of them are GDPR compliant and protect your data to at least the same standard that we do ourselves.
Your physical address and phone number are only ever stored by us and are not shared with any other companies.
If you ask us to send you our Left-Handers Club email newsletters, we will use ActiveCampaign to store your name and email address and send you the emails. This page confirms that they will maintain GDPR compliance –
https://help.activecampaign.com/hc/en-us/articles/115001246324-GDPR-and-ActiveCampaign-What-you-need-to-know
If you enter a product review on our website, your name, email and comments are shared with Codepath, who provide our Soapbox review software that allows us to manage and display your comments.
If you contact us by email or complete one of the contact forms on our website, the information you enter will be shared with Google as part of the Gmail email service.  Confirmation of their GDPR compliance can be seen here –
https://www.google.com/cloud/security/gdpr/
Your right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority
If you are not happy with the way we have collected, stored or used your personal data, we will be very happy to deal with your complaint if you contact us. If, having done so, you are still not satisfied you can complain to The Information Commissioner’s Office in the United Kingdom.  Their contact details are on this web page – https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/ – or write to Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF or telephone 0303 123 1113 (local rate).
Review of this Policy
We keep this Policy under regular review. This Policy was last updated in May 2018.
Appendix
Condensed privacy statements displayed to inform visitor consent at the time details are requested.
This appendix is provided for completeness and shows the statements on privacy and data protection that you will see at various points in our website where you are asked to provide your personal information.
To keep things informative but concise, these statements are provided in “layers” of information which give a brief overview first and allow visitors to easily “drill-down” to more detail if they want it.
The layers of information are:
1.     A short statement shown actually on the page near to the entry area for the personal data being requested
2.     Where appropriate, a longer statement that opens in a pop-up window on the same page
3.     Our full Privacy policy (this document) that can be opened in a new browser window by clicking a link.
Where the information we are collecting and its purpose are made clear on the web page and we will not be using your information for any other purposes, we will put the condensed privacy statement by the “Submit” button and take your submission as sufficient affirmative action to give confirmed consent to us processing your details.
Where we are asking for permission to possible use your information for other related purposes, we will be more explicit and provide an additional “tick box” for you to affirm your consent to the additional processing.
In the checkout pages of the Anything Left-Handed shopping cart where contact details for processing an order are requested.
Short statement on the page:
We need your personal details to process and despatch your order, send you confirmations by email and contact you if there is any issue needing your response. Your details will be kept securely and not shared with anyone else for marketing purposes.
I consent to my personal details being processed by Anything Left-Handed in order to process and despatch my order
In places where people can register for the Left-Handers Club email newsletter
Short statement on the page:
We need your name and email to send you our newsletter. Your details will be kept securely and not shared with anyone else for marketing purposes.
I consent to my details being used to register me for the free Left-Handers Club and send me your newsletter, product information and offers by email (I understand I can unsubscribe at any time)
By our contact forms
Short statement on the page:
We need your name and email so we can reply to your enquiry. Your details will be kept securely and not shared with anyone else for marketing purposes.
I consent to you storing my personal details to use for responding to my enquiry
By the comments box on blog posts
Short statement on the page:
We need your name and email to record your comment and possibly reply to it.  Your details will be kept securely and not shared with anyone else for marketing purposes and only your name will be displayed on our web pages.
I consent to my comment being recorded and my name and comment displayed at the bottom of this post after it had been approved
By the Product Review entry box
Short statement on the page:
We need your name and email to record your comments and possibly reply to them.  Your details will be kept securely and not shared with anyone else for marketing purposes and your email address will not be displayed on our website.
I consent to my name and email being recorded with my review comments and for my review to be published on your website.
Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *
E-mail *
Website
Notify me of new posts by email.
This site uses Akismet to reduce spam. Learn how your comment data is processed.
5 comments on “Privacy policy”
Dr Billy Levin says:
January 21, 2019 at 1:30 pm
I have 50 years experience and 22000 cases of ADHD/ADD which is very related to handedness,
contact me. Adders.org in the UK and allexperts.org
in the USA have my research articles.
Reply
Stan says:
May 13, 2014 at 6:51 pm
To whom concern,
My 2 year old son is left handed from the beginning. Start badly nursery, where he is changed for right hand. To day called to my
local health visitor with complain. What I heard: children changing hands in age 2 and half year. May I ask kindly for help.
Concern Parent
Reply
mary Lightfoot says:
February 5, 2013 at 5:54 pm
Hello I am doing my dissertation on left handedness and how it affects children’s learning. Teacher awareness. resources and strategies. I wondered if you have any information to help or can point me in the right direction? There seems to be little on this subject as opposed to WHY people are left handed.
Thank you for your time
Mary
Reply
tom lockley says:
August 27, 2010 at 1:40 am
i used my e mail and did so not thinking that it may be used on the web ,please do not use this , it would be appreciated .. t lockley
Reply
Sue says:
August 13, 2010 at 6:11 pm
I do not seem to be receiving the club emails, but you say that I am registered. Will you check this please?
Is it Me?
You have the left hand! (in Spanish)
Ordering questions?
Store Navigation
